A Guide to the Papers of Sam Shepard ca.1975-1988
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Sam Shepard ca. 1975-1988
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10818
This collection consists of ca. 350 items.
Administrative Information
Access
Access Restricted. Contact curator for details.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited 1989 January 27.
Scope and Content Information
The collection contains manuscripts, shooting schedules, correspondence, reviews, programs, notes, sheet music, page proofs, drawings, photographs, blueprints, storyboards, posters, contracts, interviews, notebooks and awards.
Works covered include "Crimes of the heart," "Curse of the starving class," "Far north," "Fool for love," "A lie of the mind," "Motel chronicles," "Paris, Texas," and "The war in heaven."
Contents List
- Manuscripts
  - TMs Around the World in Eight Days by Ron Kovic: Uncorrected page proof (p. 1-90), 44 p., with Correspondence 1984 (Box 1)
  - TMs (EC) Baby Boom: Shooting Script with autograph revisions, and notes on sequence by Sam Shepard, 124 p. 1986 Oct 27 (Box 1)
  - TMs (EC) Conversation with Sam Shepard in Rolling Stone by Jonathan Cott, with autograph revisions, 54 p. 1986 Mar (Box 1)
  - Country: Shooting Schedules and Production Information 1983, 18 items (Box 1)
  - TMs (EC) Crimes of the Heart: Shooting Script with annotations by Sam Shepard, 120 p. 1986 Apr (Box 1)
  - TMs Curse of the Starving Class: Screenplay, with autograph annotations by Sam Shepard, 120 p. 1987 (Box 1)
  - Deep in the Heart: Reviews 1984 Jan, 3 items (Box 1)
  - TMs Denial: Screenplay with autograph revisions and additional notes by Sam Shepard, 48 p. n.d. (Box 1)
  - TMs Dylan Songs with autograph revisions, 4 p. n.d. (Box 1)
  - TMs Far North: Screenplay, First Draft, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 80 p. 1986 (Box 1)
  - Far North: Screenplay, early draft, with autograph annotations and camera directions by Sam Shepard, 106 p. 1987 Feb (Box 1)
  - Far North: Shooting Schedules 1987 Apr-May, 10 items (Box 1)
  - Far North: Correspondence 1987 Apr-July,1988, n.d., 23 items (Box 2)
  - TMs Far North: Screenplay with autograph camera directions by Sam Shepard, 132 p. 1987 June (Box 2)
  - TMs Far North: Screenplay, Final Draft, with slight autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 131 p. 1987 June (Box 2)
  - TMs Far North: Screenplay, Shooting Script, with extensive autograph camera directions by Sam Shepard, 175 p. 1987 Oct-Nov, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Far North: Wild Track Log 1987 Oct-Nov, 1 item, binder (Box 2)
  - Far North: Notes for Set Design 1987, notebook (Box 3)
  - TMs (EC) Far North: Screenplay with autograph camera directions by Sam Shepard, 105 p. 1987 (Box 3)
  - Far North: Annotated Script of the Screenplay with copies of one line breakdown 1987-1988, 1 item, binder (Box 3)
  - TMs Far North: Article, Sam Shepard and Far North by Jonathan Cott, 13 p., with ANS by Sam Shepard on cover n.d. (Box 3)
  - Far North: Strips for Scene Board n.d. (Box 3)
  - Fool for Love/The Sad Lament of Pecos Bill on the Eve of Killing his Wife, with extensive autograph annotations by Sam Shepard for the Screenplay of Fool for Love 1979, printed (Box 3)
  - TMs Fool for Love, with slight autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 86 p. 1982 Dec (Box 3)
  - TMs (EC) Fool for Love: Screenplay for Magic Theatre performance, 63 p. 1983 Jan (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: Rehearsal Script with autograph revisions and stage directions by Sam Shepard, 86 p. 1983 Mar (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: Contract and Correspondence with Lawrence Ferlinghetti of City Lights Books 1983, 3 items (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: Program for the Magic Theatre World Premiere 1983, printed (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: Reviews 1983, printed (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: Dramatists Play Service, Ind. edition (pages 1- 43), 23 p. 1984 Jan 13, printed (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: German Production Program 1984 Jan, printed (Box 4)
  - TMs (EC) Fool for Love: Screenplay Revisions, Third Draft, 93 p. 1985 Apr 19 (Box 4)
  - TMs (EC) Fool for Love: Screenplay Revisions, Fourth Draft, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 92 p. 1985 Apr 25 (Box 4)
  - Fool for Love: Correspondence 1985, 3 items (Box 4)
  - TMs Horse Sense: Sam Shepard Talks to Kevin Sessums in Interview magazine, 30 p., with photographs (copies) 1988 June (Box 4)
  - AMs Imaginary Sun: Present Past, 50 p. 1981 Aug (Box 4)
  - AMs Knowledge of the Seven Steps (Synthetic Tears), 115 p. 1979 Nov (Box 4)
  - TMs The Last Shot: Screenplay with autograph camera directions and six pages of notes by Sam Shepard, 139 p. 1986 Jan 28 (Box 4)
  - TMs A Lie of the Mind: First Version and Cuts, with heavy autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 169 p. 1984 May-Aug (Box 5)
  - TMs pages A Lie of the Mind: Cuts, with heavy autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 129 p. 1984 (Box 5)
  - TMs A Lie of the Mind: Second Version and Cuts, with heavy autograph revisons by Sam Shepard, 153 p. 1984 (Box 5)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Contact Sheets and Schedules 1984-1985, 15 items (Box 5)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Correspondence and Reviews 1984-1987, 18 items (Box 5)
  - TMs (EC) A Lie of the Mind: Working Script with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, bound in red cover, 195 p. 1985 Sep (Box 5)
  - TMs A Lie of the Mind: Final Script before Cuts, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 273 p. 1985 Nov (Box 5)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Production Notes 1985 (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Notes on Scenes and miscellaneous 1985, n.d., 3 items (Box 6)
  - TMs A Lie of the Mind, with slight autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 254 p. 1986 (Box 6)
  - TMs A Lie of the Mind: Draft Jacket Copy and Photographs for the Methuen London Ltd. edition 1987 Jan (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Page Proof for Methuen London Ltd. edition, 136 p. 1987 Jan (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Dutch Production Program, Reviews, and Photographs 1987 Sep-Nov, 14 items (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Cover Design and Flap Copy for the New American Library edition 1987 (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Galley Proof for the New American Library edition, 93 p. 1987 (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Swedish Production Program and Reviews 1988 Apr, 8 items (Box 6)
  - A Lie of the Mind: Norwegian Production Program and Reviews 1988 Apr-May, 11 items (Box 6)
  - TMs Machismo Sagas(unfinished), with slight autograph revisions, 25 p. 1978 Aug 27 (Box 6)
  - TMs (EC) Man Fly: Adapted from Christopher Marlowe's Doctor Faustus, 61 p. (p. 26 missing) n.d. (Box 6)
  - Motel Chronicles[working title Transfixion/(chronicles & fables [overscored and deleted])], early draft, 107 p. 1981 (Box 7)
  - TMs Motel Chronicles[working title Transfixion/(Motel Chronicles)], with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 142 p. 1981 (Box 7)
  - TMs Motel Chronicles[working title Transfixion(deleted by Laurence Ferlinghetti)], with annotations by Ferlinghetti., 117 p. 1981 (Box 7)
  - TMs (EC) Motel Chronicles, 141 p. 1981 (Box 7)
  - Motel Chronicles: Contract 1982 (Box 7)
  - Motel Chronicles: Reviews 1983, 4 items (Box 7)
  - TMs Motel Chronicles: Page Proofs for Redwood Burn Limited edition (p. 1-188), 95 p. 1984 Sept 24 (Box 7)
  - TMs The Only Thing We knew for Sure about Henry Porter by Stephen Scobie, 46 p. 1987 (Box 7)
  - Opportunities (7 movements): Synopsis of the Five Acts, 8 p. n.d. (Box 7)
  - TMs (EC) Paris, Texas: Screenplay, 247 p. 1982 (Box 8)
  - TMs Paris, Texas: Film Outline (Description), with re-writes and autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 123 p. 1983 Feb 22 (Box 8)
  - Paris, Texas: Descriptive Script with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 147 p. 1983 Sep (Box 8)
  - Paris, Texas: Background Story and Summary, 20 p. 1983 Oct (Box 8)
  - TMs Paris, Texas: Final re-writes for Screenplay, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 43 p. 1983 Nov (Box 8)
  - TMs Paris, Texas: Screenplay, Final Re-writes, 188 p. 1983 Nov (Box 8)
  - TMs Paris, Texas: Outline, Second Draft, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, including color illustrations, 140 p. 1983 (Box 8)
  - AMs Paris, Texas: First and Second Scenes, 19 p. [1983] (Box 9)
  - TMs pages Paris, Texas: Dialogue with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard and Wim Wenders, 108 p. [1983] (Box 9)
  - TMs pages Paris, Texas: Re-writes of Scenes, with slight autograph revisions, 106 p. [1983] (Box 9)
  - TMs (EC) Paris, Texas: Dialogue List, Road Movies, 107 p. 1984 Apr (Box 9)
  - Paris, Texas: Program and Newspaper Articles re showing at Cannes Film Festival 1984, 17 items (Box 9)
  - TMs (EC) Red Cross: French version, translation by Dominique Meyer, 27 p. 1986 Jan (Box 9)
  - TMs (EC) Red Woman/Padua, 3 p. 1978 July (Box 9)
  - Rolling Thunder Revue: Tour Personnel 1975, 3 items (Box 9)
  - TMs The Sad Lament of Pecos Bill on the Eve of Killing His Wife, with slight autograph revisions, 9 p. 1976 July (Box 9)
  - T he Sad Lament of Pecos Bill on the Eve of Killing His Wife: Musical Score by Sam Shepard and Catherine Stone 1983 Apr (Box 9)
  - The Sad Lament of Pecos Bill on the Eve of Killing His Wife: Musical Score by Sam Shepard and Catherine Stone [1983] (Box 9)
  - TMs Savage Love: Production Script with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 23 p. 1979 Aug (Box 9)
  - TMs Savage Love, 23 p. [1979] (Box 9)
  - 3 TMs (EC) Savage Love, 23 p. each [1979] (Box 9)
  - TMs Side to Side: Interview Play, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 35 p. 1986 Aug (Box 9)
  - TMs Side to Side: Interview Play, with autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 30 p. 1986 Sep (Box 9)
  - TMs Tongues, with slight autograph revisions, 1978 Sep 29 (Box 9)
  - TMs True West, 96 p. 1979 Sep (Box 10)
  - TMs (EC) True West, 96 p. 1979 Sep (Box 10)
  - TMs True West, 127 p. [1979] (Box 10)
  - TMs True West, with slight autograph revisions by Sam Shepard, 110 p. [1979] (Box 10)
  - TMs (EC) True West: French version, L'Quest, Le Vrai, translation and adaptation by Rudi Coupez, 56 p. n.d. (Box 10)
  - TMs (EC) Until the End of the World by Wim Wenders and Solveig Dommartin: Revised Draft of the Screenplay by Michael Almereyda, 157 p. 1987 May 16 (Box 10)
  - TMs Untitled, an interaction between a teacher and a student in a surrealistic manner, 7 p. n.d. (Box 10)
  - AMs Untitled, beginning "I remember the first afternoon of my father's collapse...," 1 p. n.d. (Box 10)
  - TMs The War in Heaven(Angel's Monologue): First Version, with autograph revisions by Shepard, 17 p. 1984 Aug (Box 10)
  - TMs The War in Heaven(Angel's Monologue): Second Version, with autograph revisions by Shepard, 29 p. 1984 Aug (Box 10)
- Letters
  - Letter from Woody Allen 1987 May (Box 10)
  - Letter from Marlon Brando (electrostatic copy) 1987 June (Box 10)
  - Letters from Joseph Chaikin 1983-1988, 13 items (Box 10)
  - Letters from Johnny Dark, with material re Andrew Wyeth 1983, 1987, 4 items (Box 10)
  - Letters from Tom Waits 1986 Oct-Nov, 3 items (Box 10)
  - Letters from Writers and others 1978-1988, n.d., 10 items (Box 10)
- Miscellaneous
  - Notes on Blues Film 1986 Aug, notebook (Box 10)
  - Notes on A Lie of the Mind 1984 Oct-Nov, notebook (Box 10)
  - Notes on Motel Chronicles 1980 Jan, bound vol. (Box 10)
  - Notes on The War in Heaven, and personal memoranda 1984 Jan, notebook (Box 11)
  - Notes on Ideas for Plays 1979-1980, notebook (Box 11)
  - Notes on Ideas for Plays 1983 Jan-June, notebooks (Box 11)
  - Notes on Ideas for Plays 1984, notebook (Box 11)
  - Pencil Drawings by Sam Shepard 1985-1986, 11 items (Box 11)
  - Pencil Drawings, chiefly of male faces, by Shepard 1986 Aug, notebook (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Sam Shepard adn other n.d, 18 items (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Sam Shepard playing polo n.d., 3 items (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Sam Shepard and Jessica Lange in Frances n.d., 5 items (Box 11)
  - Photographs of Sam Shepard in The Right Stuff 1982, 5 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs of Buried Child n.d., 6 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs of Curse of the Starving Class n.d., 6 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs of The Unseen Hand n.d., 9 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs for Savage Love and Suicide Bb 1978-1979, 12 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs (contact sheets) of Fool for Love, Magic Theatre, San Francisco 1983, 18 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs of Fool for Love, Magic Theatre, San Francisco 1983, 34 items (Box 11)
  - Production Photographs of Fool for Love, New York 1983, 11 items (Box 11)
- Memorabilia
  - Brandeis University Creative Arts Award/Theater Arts/ Sam Shepard 1984
  - Drama Desk Award for Outstanding New Play Presented to Sam Shepard for A Lie of the Mind 1985
  - The Laurence Olivier Awards Nomination Presented to Sam Shepard for A Lie of the Mind 1987, framed
- Oversize
  - Plays
    - Balm in Gilead: Blueprint for floor plan of Minetta Lane Theatre 1984
    - Far North: Mockups for display posters [1987], 2 items
    - Far North: Storyboard including nine pencil drawings, with directional notes in red ink [1987]
    - Fool for Love: Blueprint for ground plan of Circle Repetory Theatre [1983]
    - A Lie of the Mind: Line drawing for rough ground plan of Promenade Theatre 1985
    - A Lie of the Mind: Display posters advertising the Dutch production at Rotterdam Theater 1987, 3 items
    - A Lie of the Mind: Reviews of the Swedish production at Gotesborgs Stadsteater 1988 Apr 10-12, 4 items
    - A Lie of the Mind: Reviews of the Norwegian production at Det Norske Teatret 1988 Apr 23-26, 10 items
    - Mad Dog Blues: Display poster advertising the Italian version n.d.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Pencil drawing of man with hat facing right by Sam Shepard, New Mexico 1985 June
    - Pencil drawing of city scenes by Sam Shepard, New York City 1985 Sep
    - Photographs (electrostatic copies) of Sam Shepard: six facial close-ups, one of hands, three with horse n.d., 10 items
    - Calendar photograph of Hampton's Ford Stage Station Barn, Box Elder County, Utah n.d.